George A. Parkinson Papers
George A. Parkinson Papers
1937-1963
Parkinson, George A.
.25 linear ft.
Speeches on adult education topics.
149445
Biographical History
George A. Parkinson was a member of the Milwaukee University of Wisconsin Extension (1937-1956) and director of the Milwaukee Teachers College (1958-1968). He served many posts as board member and officer of the Association of University Evening Colleges. He was active in bringing educational television to Milwaukee. He also served ETV both regionally and nationally as Vice President of the Midwest ETV Association (1962- ) and as a board member of the National Instructional Television Library (1962- ).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The George A. Parkinson Papers consists of his speeches extending from 1937 to 1963, and ranging in subject matter from "The Role of the Evening College in Community Education," to "A Pattern of Higher Education for the State of Wisconsin" to "Education Beyond the High School and Where Vocation and Adult Education Fit Into the Picture."
Arrangement of the Collection
Speeches are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
In particular, see also:
Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC) Records
National University Extension Association (NUEA) Records.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Parkinson, George A.; Association of University Evening Colleges (U.S.); Adult education -- United States.; Adult education -- Wisconsin.; Educators -- United States.; Evening and continuation schools -- United States.; Speeches (documents); Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Speeches
  - "Some Aspects of Adult Education", 2 Feb 1937; ts, 7 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Report on the Investigation of Evening School Students at the Milwaukee Center in the Spring of 1937", [1937]; ts, 8 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Adult Education for Adults", 9 Feb 1938; ts, 15 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Modern Aspects of Adult Education", [ca.1938]; ts, 13 pp. (Box 1)
  - "What Does the Veteran of Foreign Wars Expect of the Public Schools?", 26 Mar 1946; ts, 4 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Should an Additional Year Be Added to the Present Four-Year High School Curriculum?", 8 Apr 1946; ts, 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - "What Is the Meaning of Education?", 10 Dec 1946; ts, 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - "The Philosophy of an Educator", 19 Dec 1946; ts, 10 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Who Should Go to College", 31 Jul 1947; ts, 7 pp. (Box 1)
  - "The Role of the Evening College in Community Education", 11 Nov 1947; ts, 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - "A Pattern of Higher Education for the State of Wisconsin", 17 Nov 1947; ts, 16 pp. (Box 1)
  - "A Mathematician Looks at Education", 16 Jan 1949; ts, 8 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Patterns for the Future", 1956; ts, 10 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Education versus Social and Industrial Change", 18 Feb 1958; ts, 5 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Education and Survival in an Atomic Age", 15 Sep 1958; ts, 9 pp. (Box 1)
  - Commencement Address at Milwaukee Boy's Technical. High School, 26 Jan 1959; ts, 9 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Education versus Social and Industrial Change", 18 Mar 1959; ts, 5 pp. (2 copies) (Box 1)
  - "Education Beyond High School and Where the Vocational and Adult Schools Fit into the Picture", 8 Sep 1959; ts, 8 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Adult Education and Automation", 27 Apr 1961; ts, 4 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Education and Social and Industrial Change", 6 Jun 1961; ts, 9 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Some Reflections on Basic Trends Affecting Our Educational Patterns", 10 Apr 1962; ts, 9 pp. (Box 1)
  - "Some Aspects of Vocational and Technical Education", 9 Oct 1962; ts, 8 pp. (Box 1)
  - "The Philosophy and Operation of the Milwaukee Vocational and Adult. Schools", [Spring 1963]; ts, 7 pp. (Box 1)